Today on the podcast, I sat down with Nathan McCauley, the co-founder and CEO of Anchorage.
As many who listen to this podcast will know, Anchorage operates a federally chartered bank
and they're a major player in the digital asset custody and stablecoin ecosystem,
along with many other product lines. This was a timely episode where we talked about
the debanking of crypto companies, talked about upcoming policy milestones and priorities,
including crypto executive orders, SAV 121 repeal, stablecoin legislation, market structure bill,
and a lot more. We also talked about the work that Anchorage is doing with institutions and
protocols, the global dollar network, as well as new product launches on the horizon.
Think you'll enjoy this one, so without further ado, here's my conversation with Nathan McCauley.
The Bank of England has pumped 75 billion pounds more to Britain's ailing economy,
with a new round of clubs to do easy. All right, Nathan, thanks so much for joining us
today on the podcast. I can't believe you haven't been on this podcast before, so appreciate you
coming on. I've been a long time fan, Matt, so very glad to be here. Thanks for having me.
And what a week to have you on. So you testified in front of the Senate Banking Committee. That's
got to be a stressful week for you. So one of those things where it's obviously a very high stakes
situation, certainly never would have imagined doing something like that when I'm taking the
public speaking classes back in college, but nevertheless, was asked to come and tell our
story there, so had a fun time there testifying in Senate Banking Committee this week.
Definitely want to get into all of that. People that listen to this podcast probably know a good
deal about Anchorage, but for those maybe who are less familiar, can you maybe just set the table
with the company a little bit of the origin story and the lines of business that you guys are in
today? Sure, thanks. So Anchorage is here to serve institutions who want to participate in
broadly digital asset ecosystem. And so about seven years ago, me and my co-founder Diogo
started the company on the assumption that institutions would want to come into digital
assets. And at the time, late 2017, early 2018, there were a ton of people in retail
that were participating in digital assets, but basically no institutional offerings. There
wasn't institutional custodians. There were very few that I think the most institutional trading
venue you had was Coinbase Pro. And so it was just a white space. And the basic bet was, hey,
if this is going to be an asset class, it's not going to be entirely driven by retail,
it'll also be driven by institutions. And so let's build a set of tools for institutional
investors. The natural starting point on that journey was digital asset custody, particularly
some of the large investors have to satisfy what's called the qualified custody rule. So they
need to hold assets with a qualified custodian. And so we started out with a custody system that
really is still kind of the central point of our company. That's our largest business line and the
biggest set of value that we bring to the clients is a safe and secure custody solution. We wanted
to take a little bit of a contrarian take with the way that we built custody. We were not interested
in the cold storage solutions where you have to take the assets, take them offline, and then never
get to touch them. We assumed that the digital asset ecosystem would mean that you would actually
want to do stuff with the digital assets. What we now understand to be things like staking,
things like participating in DeFi governance. So the basic tenant at the beginning was people want
to do stuff with their assets, they want to hold it in a super safe way, and they want the whole
thing to be regulated. And so along that journey, we pursued regulatory licensure from the very
beginning of the company, and then that eventually culminated in us getting the federal bank
charter we have with the OCC. So this has been a large part of our differentiation is the fact
that we have this national bank charter. We can hold a whole host of digital assets for
institutional investors. And maybe just wrapping up on this right now, what this means is that we
serve basically all of the large holders and types of holders of digital assets, whether it's the
VC funds that hold their tokens, their holding that they've invested in, the digital asset protocols
themselves. A lot of protocols decide that they'll TGE with us and hold their initial supply
with Anchorage and then use us as the distribution mechanism out for that. And then ETF issuers
hold their assets at Anchorage as a safe, qualified custodial bank for those assets,
all the way up to some of the world's sovereign wealth funds that's used to hold their assets
with us. So it's kind of that whole landscape of digital asset investors hold their assets with us.
Along that trajectory, it made sense to add additional services. And so we provide staking
services for them. We provide trading services and tri-party and settlement services, really
all of the stuff that an institution needs in order to support their investment thesis and grow
their business. And that's really where we focus. I can definitely attest as a user or customer that
it's an exceptional platform. The tech is incredible. I think one of the more interesting
things that you did highlight there is just the way that you guys went about becoming a qualified
custodian, going this OCC path. It's pretty remarkable giving everything that's happened
over the past three, four years. That was a pathway that you were able to achieve.
Maybe talk a little bit about what that process was like and maybe what it's been like
after you got the charter. It's a great question. It's been a really funny and fun story for us.
That's played out a lot of different ways, some of them quite surprising. But generally speaking,
we wanted to solve this qualified custody rule for our clients. That meant that we ourselves
needed to get regulated. At the time, this was an impossible problem. No one knew how digital
asset firms should be regulated, how they should be set up. The initial starting hypothesis was
actually to try to get a broker dealer. Broker dealers are allowed to be qualified custodians.
Spent a bunch of time on that and ended up being a little bit of a dead end. And then we pivoted
from that strategy to get a state charter trust company. State charter trust company that we got
out of South Dakota allowed us to start operating. We were able to access a qualified custodian.
A lot of our initial growth happened once we got that charter in South Dakota. Opportunity
presented itself in the last year of the Trump administration, where there was an opportunity
to convert our state charter into a national trust bank. And so we went through a conversion process
where we turned that state chartered institution into a federally chartered institution. It took
a lot of work, obviously. It's a very serious thing to create a national bank. Lots of compliance
processes needed. Really, when you create a national bank, the way the government views it is that
you're creating literally a permanent entity. It is expected that the thing that gets created
is a permanent fixture. Early on in the process, they wanted to talk about things like continuity
plans, like what happens when I retire. And at some point, I was like, you guys, I'm 35.
That's not something we need to worry about yet. But that's the kind of time frames we're thinking
about when you create a national bank. And so we completed that conversion process. And so in early
January of 2021, we started operating as a national bank. This was huge for us because
there's a lot of industry participants that took that signal like, hey, we got a national bank
crypto now. That's almost a tacit approval that is possible to do this business. It's possible to
participate in the digital asset ecosystem. A lot of clients and client growth came as a result
of getting that charter. Interestingly, in our charter, we actually got four activities that
were allowed to do with our charter. Custody of digital assets, staking of digital assets,
settlement of digital assets, and governance of digital assets. This is pretty cool because of
that staking and governance ones. To my knowledge, we're actually the first incarnations of the
federal government saying that those activities weren't even legal and weren't even allowed at all,
the participating in staking, participating in governance. And so we're really proud of that.
And to use that to really grow the business on board a lot of clients and really provide a lot
of value to the ecosystem. It's been crazy to see that pathway just got shut down after you guys
got it, at least from my perspective. And so what was your view on just the ability to retain
that license even? It had to have been pretty hairy over the past couple of years, just given
all of the operation choke point type of activities that were going on in the industry.
Yeah, it ends up being an interesting thing. So when banks get chartered, as mentioned, I think
my team did some research on this. The OCC was actually established by Abraham Lincoln. And as
far as we understand it, there has not been an OCC charter that's been revoked since Abraham
Lincoln established the OCC. And so there's kind of this long history that speaks to exactly what
I talked about earlier, which is the charters are permanent. They are a permanent institution.
Now, that's not to say that things can't be made quite difficult and existing and working
under that regulatory scrutiny. But in a lot of ways, I think the regulatory scrutiny that we were
under is why a lot of clients trusted us. Particularly, I would say, a lot of other
national banks. There were a lot of other national banks and state banks that were
actively looking at partnerships with us because of the fact that we had that charter.
And they said to themselves, okay, we don't want to become a custodian ourselves, but we'd like
to participate in the digital asset ecosystem. Why don't we build out a business model, whether
it's using Anchorage as a sub custodian, referring clients over and then lending against those assets,
or thinking about things with tokenization, where Anchorage could be a partner to us. And so they
handle the regulatory licensure of the custody of the digital assets, but we can build a crypto
business and use them as infrastructure. This is actually common with custody banks,
BNY, State Street, Northern Trust. Many of them act as the custodian for the other banks. And so
this was a very nicely growing opportunity for us there directly after our chartering process.
That makes sense. I want to talk a little bit about the debanking over the past few years.
So we became aware of this, I would say, just from our vantage point of trying to fund early
stage businesses and some of them having a really hard time getting bank accounts. And
other companies are a portfolio just getting cashier's checks from their banks and saying,
look, you're shut down, take the money elsewhere and really panicking and having to scramble to
make payroll, try to get onboarded somewhere else. When did you become aware that there was
some sort of a coordinated activity against the crypto industry? And curious what your journey
was in terms of getting vocal about it? Because I think you've done a great service for the industry
and just talking to some of the politicians and making it broadly aware that, look, something
bad is happening here. Yeah, I think that the first indication on our side actually of that
was not what you guys have correctly identified as debanking industry-wide. Our first indication of
it was those very partnerships that I was just talking about, the large national banks and regional
banks that wanted to get into digital assets. Literally, we're looking at building digital
asset businesses, paused those partnership conversations. So this is the first hint that
something is wrong, because we've got like an industry-wide trend that all of a sudden vanishes.
All of a sudden, nobody is interested in becoming a subs custodian. Nobody is interested in lending
against digital assets. Nobody is interested in doing all these kinds of things. But I think
that's actually really important to note here that all of them were actively trying to become
crypto banks themselves. That's the starting point mental model I have in your head. Banks
wanted to come into crypto and were actively working on it. And so those things start to dry up.
And then we see a steady stream of regulatory filings. Maybe some people would call them rules,
interpretations, really across a broad swath of the industry. A lot of the attention in the industry
focused on this particularly, I don't know, hilarious one called SAB 121, which was a deeply
specific accounting interpretation that made it impossible for any national bank to come to digital
assets because of the way they would have to reserve against those assets. So that one got a
lot of press. I want to spend a bunch of time on that. Related to that, those of us that are
in the banking industry and follow the banking nerds, if you will, saw a bunch of these coming
out. FDIC had their own interpretive letter that came out. The OCC had interpretive letter
called OCC interpretive letter 1179 that specified that it was actually interpretation that they had
that said you have to come and ask us if you want to do anything with digital assets. Typically,
banks are allowed to do whatever they want. They have to follow what are called safety and
soundness guidelines, but they have broad flexibility to almost self-regulate. The way
the banks are set up is they have a whole set of internal processes that functionally act as a
self-regulatory system. And then the regulators come in and look at those and make sure that
the machine that is the self-regulatory apparatus inside the bank is continuing to run as stated.
If you get to the point where your real regulators trust you that much, that's what you're able to
do. And so this letter that comes out of the OCC says, no, you can't decide for yourself on this
anymore. You got to come ask us if you can do anything on that. And our understanding is all
of those conversations terminated in, don't do it. Like they said, you got to come ask and then
don't do it. That's what happened there. Adding on to that, there's this joint letter that came
out from Fed, FDIC, and OCC that starts out in its preamble. Banks can do whatever they want.
And then follows up with, here's a laundry list, a litany of risky things. And then concludes with,
we think doing this stuff is highly unlikely to be consistent with safe and sound banking
practices, which to most people is, okay, that's like a pretty boring drab statement,
but it's actually like an outright ban. When you see highly unlikely to be inconsistent with safe
and sound banking practices, every bank CEO in the country reads that. Okay, I see what they're
trying to say. Do not do that. And so then after that one, that's where we actually saw what you
guys have described as debanking. This is where people started losing their accounts. This is
where people started getting kicked off the platforms. I've heard about this in some cases
from my, I have a bit of an angel investment. I like to invest in my friends, invest in other
people around and started to hear stories of people losing their bank accounts. And then
the culmination of that was it actually happened to us. And so that was a nice part of the Senate
testimony is like talking a little bit about the story that actually happened to us as a
national bank getting debanked. So I guess after all of this, and you're down there this week,
you're testifying from the Senate banking, are you optimistic that this is changing the
new roster, the cast of characters down there or understanding what happened and taking corrective
action? Yeah, I am. I think that if you look at the point of this hearing that we had this week,
it was really just about getting the ideas out there. The Senate in particular wanted to cast a
broad brush on what's happening here. And so I was the one crypto witness where I talked about
how this has happened within the crypto industry. But then they within the Senate wanted to talk
about general problem, particularly because I think President Trump is interested in this idea of
potentially conservatives getting debanked, other disfavorite industries also getting
debanked. And so it's like a broad question of how do we, and just at this point, understand
shine a light on what happened here. And so that was really the point of this hearing.
And that's the one where I shared the anchorage story of getting debanked, which I don't want to
spend a bunch of time on it. But broadly speaking, we had a bank that we had a growing relationship
with. We've had them for several years, actively discussing new partnerships. And then just one
day, they call us and say, Hey, it's over, your account is closed. And this is particularly ironic
because we are a national bank ourselves. There couldn't be a more regulated, safe partner to
work with within the digital asset industry. It's like a banking account, a basic checking account
for a bank. And so us getting our account closed was used as illustrative purpose in the banking
hearing instead of making a hearing just to talk about like where this kind of happened,
how pervasive it was. And so step one is shine a light on this. There's some discussion about
what could happen moving forward. I think there's kind of two camps emerging on which way things
should go. And so at least in some sense, there's some room for optimism here in that maybe the
Republican side is looking at, okay, how do we make sure that this doesn't happen anymore on behalf
of regulatory overreach, if you will. And then I would say, nicely, even someone like Senator
Warren is looking at this and saying, how do we make sure that this doesn't happen to
disfavored political groups, whether it's some of the groups that she mentioned, minority groups
that may have had a debanking happen, all the way to the idea of conservatives being debanked,
general agreement across both sides of the aisle, that this isn't the way that policy should get
carried out. Shouldn't be the people who lose their bank accounts due to political disfavor,
due to discrimination, if you will. Overall, it felt like pretty positive. And I'm going to be
carefully tracking where we go from here. I'm really excited to see where we go and
want to dive a little bit into some of the policy milestones here that are about to happen. And in
some cases just did happen. And maybe we could look at them a little bit just through the lens of
how positive they are for Anchorage, because I think there's a lot of positive momentum here.
You mentioned SAP 121. And I think this is just fascinating if you look at it through the lens
of, okay, the banks can now play in the custody space. Very few of them have really embarked
down the mission of building their own custody stack. And so if you're on the inside of one of
these bigger banks that plays in the non-crypto custody space, you're probably having a build
versus buy versus partner conversation here. And I would have to think a lot of those institutions
would be looking at sub custody as just the fastest way to get something out. Is that the
right way to think about what's about to happen here in the broader banking space?
Yeah, I think that's exactly what's going to happen. The reason we've been consistently against
SAP 121, despite the fact that it basically cut out the whole industry from competing with us.
So one interpretation of it is it gave us a monopoly on crypto banking, which is cool.
But on the other hand, it's kind of un-American as well. And so our basic thing to regulators there
was maybe this isn't the best. And a lot of the reason for that is exactly what you said.
Most of the banks are going to want to choose a sub custodian partner that they'll want to work
with. And they're going to choose to work with a national bank. We had already kicked off a bunch
of those conversations before some of this got shut down. Those are picking up and already picking
up in earnest in a real way. So I expect one of the themes of our public messaging for the rest
of the year is going to be announcing some of these partnerships where Wall Street firms are
going to decide, hey, it's time to partner with a digital asset firm in order to get something to
market. And that that's the way to get to market fast, deliver value to your clients and get this
really going. The alternative path is to decide to become a custodian themselves and build it
internally. You're at fidelity for a long time. What they have pulled off is a modern business
miracle. It is incredible that they have built a custody system internally that holds Bitcoin.
People should write books about how incredible that effort has succeeded. But I think a lot of
people look at that. The great success there has thus far only gotten them to Bitcoin. And that's
just not the shape of the ecosystem. There are so many different assets. And so people look at
even just like the asset support complexity over time and say, hey, if we want to really
participate in this space, it's going to have to be a partner program where we partner with somebody.
And I think a lot of them are going to decide, hey, this is not just tech that we need. It's also
regulatory solve and working like an anchorage gets us both at the same time.
I would love to be on the inside of some of these board discussions at these banks specifically
because you look at this and say, okay, we could build it, but is that three years? Is that four
years? How many people are we going to have to hire? Can we actually hire the right people?
Or then you look at M&A, and there just actually aren't that many things to buy.
It seems like a very interesting market structure where there's just not a lot of options. And I
would think that the subcustody just becomes the fastest way to get something out.
I think that's right. The amount of recruiting that needs to happen in order to build a team that
can build this whole thing, and then you have to retain them through down cycles.
You have to keep your composure as crypto goes into a bear market,
continue working on it through the bear market. If you're trying to get something done on a
reasonable time horizon, partnership ends up being the way to actually have success.
And you're right. There's putting a bluntly, there's many banks that would like to come in
and relatively few custodians. Like I mentioned before, this isn't a surprising situation.
This is how most of the large banks choose to implement custody anyways,
is they'll partner with a BMI or State Street to be their custodian bank. They'll stay into the
other businesses that are more in their lane. And so assuming that that will happen within the
digital asset ecosystem is actually, you might even say the base case assumption of how this
market structure plays out. Yeah, that's spot on. So I want to talk next about stablecoins.
It seems like the stablecoin bill is the one that could potentially get brought up
before market structure, although I'd love your thoughts on that. But it seems like stablecoins
are pretty far down the path of having some sort of a bipartisan consensus. There's bills
that have been drafted in the House and the Senate. I want to get your view on just where
that legislation is. And then we'd love to use that as an opportunity to talk about
global dollar network and how you guys have thought about playing the stablecoin space.
This is a funny one, Matt. I think the new administration coming in is just moving incredibly
quickly. And this speed of execution almost feels contagious. And so in a lot of the conversations
I had in the Senate, even over the last couple of weeks, has been like, hey, we want to move,
we want to move quick. We want to follow in that wake. We had the incredible press conference
from David Sacks, where David got up with congressional leadership and Senate leadership
to chart the course for regulatory clarity coming to the digital asset industry and specifically
talk about stablecoin bills, which then got introduced in the same day, and then the even
broader one, a brown market structure. So current best guess, which by the way, it changes all the
time, but current best guess looks like we're looking at stablecoin legislation likely coming
first, then followed by market structure. Right now, we've got two versions of these bills. We've
got the Hagerty bill in the Senate, and then the House complements to that, so that each of them
have a bunch of good ideas. And I think there's going to be room for some thoughtful debate about
the way we want to go here. But I think the larger point comes to this point that David Sacks made,
which is this must be a strategic asset of the United States. So Trump talked about that back
at Bitcoin Nashville. David Sacks is singing from the same hymnal now and talking about this
needs to happen. And so I think that's a big reason why stablecoins might be coming first,
is that they understand that this is key to dollar dominance over the next century.
I think that's spot on. And so I guess the logical next question to that is,
who's going to want to enter this market? Do you issue your own stablecoin? Do you join a
syndicate? You guys must have thought about launching your own stablecoin at some point,
I'd imagine. But what led you to this global dollar network concept?
The global dollar network is at its core. The idea there is a couple of things come to mind.
First of all, we need a regulated, globally accepted dollar. And if you just think about the way
that the dollar itself works, the way that the dollar itself works is that it's fair in that
the people that interact with the dollar are able to build business models on the dollar,
where they share in the economics. And so as an example, banks hold dollars and then they have a
direct business model they can build on top of that. Payments companies build on top of the dollar
and they have a natural business model they can build on that. Unfortunately, if you look at
something like USDC, it does not have a model where you can actually build on it together.
What happens with USDC is all of the yield, all of the financial participation goes to two entities
that one of those entities happens to be competitive with the entire crypto market.
And so that's like a little bit of a bummer there. All things considered, it would have been nice to
not have to do something new. And if we had just had a existing stablecoin that actually could be
global infrastructure, it would have been nicer to stick with that. Unfortunately, one doesn't
exist and certainly isn't USDC. So what we need is something that actually shares in the economic
opportunity with everybody that's contributing to it. And so what happened with global dollar was
basically that notion that I just shared with you, a series of probably five, six crypto CEOs came to
me and said, hey, Nathan, can you please make a stablecoin that's fair and that we can all work
together on? Because somebody was like, hey, I've minted billions in USDC, holding hundreds of
millions and I'm getting nothing. And I was like, oh, yeah, that's true. And then you hear this enough
and you're like, okay, something else needs to happen. So that kind of nucleus is the core of
the idea of a global dollar where we can bring everybody in to this stablecoin and then they
can share in the economics. The other theory on is like, why does it need to be a consortium?
Why not just have each and every one of us make our own dollar, Anchorage dollar,
Kraken dollar, Robinhead dollar, whatever. And then that's where you come to, okay,
we need global liquidity to be able to work together. And so the consortium model I think is
the winning model where a bunch of people come together and say, hey, we're going to work together
on a stablecoin. It's going to share economics with the distributors, those who are helping to
grow the network. Those distributors can decide to however works for them, share in some of that
with their clients. But generally speaking, it should be a scalable stablecoin. And early indications
just from the reach out that we're getting there is that this is a really powerful idea. A lot of
people are coming to us and say, hey, I want to join the consortium. I want to be part of this. I want
to take global dollar and have a pronounced experience within my interface. And so I think
what you're going to see over the next several months is a lot more people join that consortium
and say, I want to be part of this. I want to be part of this global dollar that I can actually
be regulated, fair, and actually act as market infrastructure for the whole ecosystem.
I've often thought about what this would look like at true institutional scale. If you wanted to use
a stablecoin to settle overnight repos, I don't think there's anything in the market right now
that's just big enough to facilitate that and you'd have credit risk issues. But it does seem like
the consortium model is maybe the only one that could really get you to that level where you're
doing true TRAT5 settlements and taking advantage of a blockchain to cut out access to the Fed wire
window at the end of the day. Yeah, I think that's right. So it'll be interesting to see how that
plays out. The other catalyst here, I think for you guys would be a market structure bill. And
we've gone through this whole history of crypto without having clarity on tokenized securities.
And there's all sorts of ideas that have been bandied about around taking things that exist in
the real world, actually having the token itself be a security. Will Anchorage be a player in that
market as it develops here? The tokenized securities area is, it's interesting. We've,
as I mentioned earlier, been looking at broker-dealer from the very inception of the company. Always
assumed things would go in this direction that assets would be brought on chain. Stablecoins are
the first instantiation of this, but why not bring in other things? As far as I understand,
right now we are the largest custodian in the world of tokenized T-bills, tokenized money
market funds, big and biddle, big and super state, and then some of the others. We're going to be a
big player in this space. I think exactly what the economic models are for this, what drives
adoption into these assets is something that is still to be figured out. There's still some
good experimentation to be done. A lot of the experimentation, though, was hard without a market
structure bill. You're correct to point out that market structure and clarity around this is going
to drive some of what I would call the product discovery that needs to happen there. And that
product discovery will lead to the use cases that really can take hold. And so, unfortunately,
this is one where the regulatory uncertainty is maybe in meaningful ways holding back the
experimentation that is needed that is actually wanting to figure out exactly how this plays out.
And so, market structure being something that's on the docket for this year is pretty exciting.
And that we could really get that unlocked that allows the experimentation that's needed.
I've probably sound like a broken record on market structure on this podcast because I talk
about the need for a bill to get this clarity and then you figure out how the secondary trading
can work. Sometimes I forget that the SEC can actually do rule making and propose rules and
work with industry. And it actually seems like that is starting immediately, even though we
don't have a confirmed commissioner of the SEC. So, maybe you end up in a world where the SEC has
put out some proposed rules and that coalesce as well into a market structure bill.
I think that's actually a really important point to make. And this is not specific to the SEC.
The SEC can release interpretive guidance that provides a clear road. The banking regulators
can provide interpretive guidance and pretty clear road. And so can the CFTC.
And so, actually, the federal regulatory agencies have a broad set of latitude
to themselves decide that this will happen. Where we might need to think about the market
structure bill is how each of those agencies interact. Some of the cross agency dependencies
are probably most appropriate for a bill to come through. But you're right. A broad set of
latitude and understanding can come through the regulatory agencies themselves drawing the path
forward. That market structure bill, at least in my mind, is something that has the potential
to spur just a ton of innovation and net new companies and protocols getting off the ground.
Just take a file coin, for example, and how much money they've had to spend on legal fees over the
years and have this question of, okay, is this thing a security? Is it a commodity?
But if there's actually a clear path there, I just think you'll see more protocol innovation.
I would imagine the protocol side of your business would actually benefit tremendously.
I think so. I think there's a huge amount of entrepreneurs that want to build protocols.
And I think that's part of what's been sad about some of the amount of regulatory uncertainty has
been, frankly, the number of protocols that have not come into existence. It's very natural for us
to talk about how much file coin has gone through on the debate of security or not security.
It's much harder to tell the story of the file coin that was never to be
because of people not coming into this. And I think that the underwater part of the iceberg
that is really worth considering. That's why I think you're exactly right. There's a bunch
more that'll happen once we have clarity and rules the road here.
You're an entrepreneur. You know what it's like, but you don't want to sign up for
just getting punched in the face for four years. I think there's a lot of ideas out there that
now will be attempted. So that'll be super interesting to see. I'd love to maybe just
talk a little bit about what's on deck here and what you guys have pushed out from a product
perspective as we close. Maybe talk a little bit about Porto Wallet. And I think that's been a
great product addition for Anchorage. Yeah, we got two growth areas that have been really helpful
to the overall Anchorage product suite. The first one is Porto. Second one I'll come back to is Atlas.
But Porto has been wonderful in that it takes the very nice usable aspects of the Anchorage
digital system, makes it available in a self-custody wallet so that people can decide basically use
it as software to allow them to do whatever they might want with that. A lot of the people that
are using Porto are using it for on-chain interactions. So being able to interact with
smart contracts, we got some protocols actually that are the entire orchestration of their protocol
is now running out of Porto. And so this has been a really good use case where
really just administrating the Porto call itself is happening through Porto. And then a whole host
of say funds like yourself or trading funds that are looking to do on-chain ARBs, take the Porto
infrastructure and allow them to do on-chain interactions. It's really a nice wallet in
that it allows you to do not just Ethereum-based transactions, but also other layer ones you
can work with as well. So it's very flexible, but also easy to use. And so we're pretty proud of that
and looking to see that grow over the next year. Next one I'll just mention briefly is Atlas.
Atlas is a really nice settlement tool that allows people to do both bilateral and triparty
relationships. And so the easiest example is like who goes first in OTC trade? Do I send the Bitcoin
or do you send the ETH or who sends the dollars? What Atlas allows you to do is both sides commit
and then the swap happens simultaneously. This dramatically reduces counterparty risk and we
think is going to be necessary as institutions come into the space. There's a lot of institutions
that come into crypto and the first head explode that they have is settlement isn't solved. Really
like somebody has to go first and this is debate that we have in the contracts. And so getting that
solved at an institutional level I think is going to be a big unlock to really make the whole ecosystem
and institutional infrastructure safer and feel and smell more like what traditional finance feels
like. But frankly as boring as that might sound it's actually going to be a big unlock for
institutions to be able to come in. And it turns out that once you have that base layer of safe
settlement there's all kinds of interesting stuff that you can build on that say triparty lending
agreements where people can hold assets as collateral somebody else can lend against them.
And Atlas I think is going to be really big for banks that want to come in particularly
they don't want to become the crypto custodian but they have a good amount of cash that they'd
like to lend against crypto. And so you can use Atlas to allow the clients to hold the Bitcoin
or other assets as a collateral asset for a loan and have the triparty relationship set up really
nicely so that they can perfect security interest in the collateral and use that to build up a
business model there. So Atlas and Porto I think are really a nice growth there is this year and
going to be interesting to see how they play out. I know it's not one-to-one comparable
necessarily but Atlas in some ways makes me think of the Silvergate exchange network and just how
critical the piece of infrastructure that was for a moment and it's crazy to think that as an
industry in some categories we just have inferior infrastructure than we did two or three years ago
and just seems like there's a lot to be built there on that settlement side.
It's a bit of a bummer but I think the way that we thought about it is how do you
go beyond something like a SEND or a SIGNET? What does that really look like?
And our theory on that is that it should be dollars and crypto should be able to settle
in that instant transparent way and so not just the dollar leg but that bilateral relationship
being able to build up the triparty relationships on that and so we're thinking about it as a bit
of a bigger vision than something as unfortunately basic that we no longer have which is like instant
settlement of dollars. So yeah we want to make sure that's front and center and that's almost a
spiritual successor to something like a SEND or a Silvergate. Nathan, appreciate you coming on the
podcast and thanks for all you're doing for the industry in terms of getting out there and actually
telling the story, you being the credible person that we can put in front of regulators and politicians.
It goes a long way. Where can we send people to learn more about Anchorage and the product lineup?
In a few places, Anchorage.com is our website and then feel free to hit me up. I'm Nathan
at Anchorage.com. You want to email me? I can help bring people into the ecosystem and get
started with accounts at Anchorage. Awesome. I enjoyed this. Thanks for coming on.
Thanks so much for having me, Matt. Appreciate it.
Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink with Castle Island. To find out more
about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc. To listen to all of our podcast episodes,
please go to onthebrink-podcast.com or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for listening.